

Introduction

A Software Engineering Manager with 15+ years of software development experience who quickly and successfully responds to ever-changing environments and situations, consistently achieves goals within critical project deadlines and is able to leverage an eye for detail, ensures success and quality. My progressive background in devising and executing on strategic software engineering and project management initiatives is substantial.

Education

Bachelor Of Engineering (Information technology) -2006 (Sardar Patel College of Engineering, Mumbai University)

Technical Skills

- Core Java/J2EE, Java 6, 7, 8
- JSP,ExtJs,AngularJS
- Spring, SpringBoot, Spring Data
- Apache Kafka, Lucene
- Drools bpmn,Activiti bpmn
- DWR,XML,XSD,XSLT
- Oracle11g,Sybase,DB2,MongoDB
- Splunk, Nagios,
 Control M, AppDynamics
- Fitnesse, Selenium, Cucumber
- Git,SVN,Clearcase,Maven, JIRA
- DevOps,CI/CD using Jenkins,Jules,ServiceNow

Functional Skills

- Micro Service Architecture
- Agile Leadership & Team building
- Agile Scrum Master
- People Management
- Cross Functional Leadership
- Analysis/Troubleshooting
- Test Driven Development(TDD)
- Global Stakeholder management
- Team Management
- System Resilience,
- Performance, Scalability

Priyesh Kailash Shah

☎: (+91) 9820942308 📧 : priyesh.0504@gmail.com

: Mumbai,India

in : https://www.linkedin.com/in/priyesh-shah-b8011631/

Key Accomplishments

- Awarded Best Innovation award for designing reusable components.
- Established and managed teams across geographical locations in India(Mumbai,Hyderabad,Bengaluru) and Glasgow(UK).
- Designed and implemented reusable components using micro service architecture.
- Collaborated with Stakeholders, Product Owner, UX designers, developers across teams to design the strategic platform for Equities, Fixed Income, FX business.
- Worked with the SRE team to implement Production checks and analysed Performance issues.
- Driving Architecture forums to brainstorm and come up with the best ideas to implement using Micro Service Architecture.
- Have been instrumental in organizational level initiatives such as defining and executing strategies for Recruitment, Career Tracks, Performance Management, Trainings, Team Management.

Work Experience

Vice President - Morgan Stanley, Mumbai - March 021 - till Date

- Working on a ECRR (Enterprise Client Risk Ranking) application. The application calculates client risk rank for KYC process based on Machine learning models.
- Managing team of 5+ members using agile methodology.
- Build, retain and lead a world class product development team through coaching, mentorship and technical guidance.
- Identified new/alternate features and recommended to the team. Tracked and reported efforts estimated.

Vice President - JP Morgan Chase, Mumbai - September 2013 - March 2021

- Worked on a Reference Data Account application which runs 24 X 6 with a user base of 2000 logins per day. The application manages reference data of clients for confirmations and settlement instructions.
- Managed team of 7+ members using agile methodology spread across geographical locations (Mumbai /Hyderabad /Bengaluru)
- Advocated / led best practices for performance, reliability, scalability, security and reusability using Microservice architecture.
- Understood all competency layers(Eg: UI platforms, methodologies etc.) and raised queries regarding work output.

Associate - MSCI, Mumbai - December 2011 - September 2013.

 Built, maintained and tested web applications using Java and EXTJS using DirectJngine for support teams to monitor the client jobs running against Risk architecture.

Associate - Cognizant Technology Solutions, Pune - March 2007 - November 2011

 Worked as Onsite- offshore model Team Lead directly at client location – CBOE, Chicago, USA from Sept 2008 – April 2011

Executive - NSDL, Mumbai - August 2006 - January 2007

Joined as fresher and was involved in maintenance of depository applications.